■
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
字幕來源：Tuxedo402    后期：奧秘
今天的烤子魚特別新鮮
The fish is very fresh today.
你們別客氣  多吃點
Eat up, enjoy yourself.
不好意思  打擾你們吃飯
Sorry to interrupt your dinner.
不要緊  我們到那邊坐吧
Never mind, let's sit over there.
怎么這樣晚
It's quite late?
是啊  剛下班就來了
I've just finished work.
怎么稱呼你
What should I call you?
叫我孫太太吧
You can call me Mrs. Suen.
你呢
And you?
我先生姓陳
My husband's name is Chan.
-決定了就給我電話  -好的
- Call me when you decide. - I will.
有沒有把號碼抄下
Did you write down my number?
我抄下來了
Yes, I did.
那好  我送你出去
Fine, I'll see you out.
-不用了  -要的  大家上海人嘛
- Don't trouble. - No trouble.
那么就這樣決定了
So it's agreed then.
謝謝你  我先走了
Thank you very much, I should go.
-好的  -再見
- Fine. - Bye!
慢走  再會
Take care, goodbye!
請問這里是不是有房間出租
You've a room to let?
真對不起  剛租給那位太太
Sorry, it's just been rented to that lady.
謝謝你
Thanks!
你幾個人住
How many of you?
我跟我太太兩個人
Just me and my wife.
你不妨到隔壁試試看
Why don't you try next door.
隔壁現在有房間嗎
They've a vacant room too?
是  隔壁顧先生的兒子剛結婚
Yes, Mr.Koo's son got married
搬了出去
and removed out.
房間也想找人租出去
His room's empty.
謝謝你
Thank you!
不用客氣  你去問一問吧
You're too polite, Try asking them.
謝謝
Thank you!
來  慢點  慢點啊
This way, come on.
這個不是我們的
Not that room.
怎么搞的  真麻煩
Wrong again.
小心點  把它靠在墻上
Careful, against the wall there.
小柜子放在旁邊好了
The little cupboard over there.
慢慢來
Be careful!
小心  別碰壞別人的東西
Don't break anything.
別壓壞了收音機
Not on top of the radio.
周先生
Mr.Chow.
怎么家具這樣多
You have a lot of stuff for a couple?
-這個柜不是我的  -又搬錯了
The wardrobe isn't mine, wrong again?
是不是隔壁的
It does next door?
那搬回去  搬回去
Okay, next door.
這些鞋子不是我的  是不是拿錯了
There aren't my shoes.
我想是隔壁的  拿過去吧
They must go next door.
真是巧  搬家都碰在一起
What a coincidence, moving in on same day.
怎么沒看見你先生
Is Mr.Chan here?
公司有事派他出門了
He's working abroad.
下禮拜才回來
He'll be back next week.
那你該等他回來再搬嘛
You should have waited, then.
搬家那么辛苦  你一個人應付得了嗎
It's too much for you on your own?
-沒關系  -叫王媽幫忙
- I can manage. - I'll ask Amah to help.
別客氣  孫太太  我自己行的
No need, I can manage.
怎么回事
What's going on?
小心那鏡子
Mind that mirror.
陳太太  你繼續收拾好了
Mrs. Chan, I'll leave you to it.
-這些書不是我的  -又錯了
- Those books aren't mine. - Wrong again?
不要緊  先放下吧
Never mind, just leave them there.
小心點  不要碰到鏡子
Mind how you hang the mirror it's fragile.
這些雜志是不是你的
Are these magazines yours?
是的  我先生的
Yes, they're my husband's.
你先生懂日文啊
He reads Japanese?
懂一點  他老板是日本人
A little, his boss is Japanese.
還沒請教你貴姓
How should I address you?
我先生姓陳
My husband's name is Chan.
我姓周  我先回去了
My name's Chow I'll leave you in peace.
謝謝你周先生
Thank you, Mr.Chow.
不客氣
Don't mention it.
我去叫陳太太
I'll ask Mrs. Chan.
陳太太  跟我們一起吃飯吧
Mrs. Chan, eat with us before you go.
我不吃了  我趕時間  我得去機場
No thanks, I must dash to the airport.
-你先生回來了  -是的
- Your husband's coming back? - Yes.
那我不耽誤你了
Then I won't keep you.
-出去呀  -晚安
- Going out? - Yes.
對不起  我遲了
Sorry, I'm late.
王媽  快點倒酒
Amah, pour some beer.
干杯
Cheers!
周太太  嘗一嘗我們的上海家常菜
Mrs. Chow, try some.
我自己來就行了
Shanghai dishes.
陳太太到哪里去了
Where is Mrs. Chan to so late?
她去接飛機嘛  她先生回來了
Meeting here husband at the airport.
怪不得打扮得那么漂亮
So that's why she looks different.
我都幫你收拾好了  你自己小心點
It's all packed, take care on your trip.
知道了
I will.
你這回去好久嗎  帶那么多東西
How long this time?
是呀  要一兩個月
Two to four weeks.
你記得回來的時候
Remember when you come back.
帶兩個你上回送給我的皮包
Bring back two more of those handbags.
誰要
Who for?
我老板
Mr.Boss.
兩個那么多
Two of them?
你知道啦
You know why.
那要不要同顏色
Different colours?
一樣顏色行了  管它呢
The same will do? Who cares?
吶  可是你說的
Whatever.
何太太嗎  我是蘇秘書呀
Mrs. Ho.
何先生現在還在談事情
Mr.Ho is still in a meeting.
他說今晚會晚回家
He'll be home late.
叫你們別等他吃飯
Please don't wait to eat.
是啊  我們這陣子很忙
Yes, we're so busy at the moment.
我請他忙完了給你打電話
Yes, I'll ask him to call you when he gets back.
給我太太打過電話了
Did you call my wife?
打過了  我說你會晚一點回去
Yes, I said you'd be back later.
幫我訂了位沒有
Have you booked the restaurant?
訂了  八點兩位
A table for two at eight.
余小姐剛來電話  她說馬上要出門
Miss Yu called to say.
叫你快點
She's on her way.
吃過飯我就回來
I'll be back after dinner.
要不要帶點東西給你吃
can I bring you something?
不客氣  我自己出去吃就行了
No thanks, I'll get my own.
如果你辦完事情我還沒回來
Leave when you're ready.
你先走  我來鎖門好了
I'll lock up.
何先生  你走了
Good evening, Mr.Ho. Evening?
-陳太太  出去呀  -是的
- Going out, Mrs.Chan? - Yes.
這時候還要出去呀
Going out so late?
我去買面
Just getting some noodles.
王媽在弄蹄膀湯  大家一塊吃
Amah is making pork soup, join us.
別客氣  我不是太餓  我想出去走走
Thanks, I'm not really hungry. I just want some air.
-不要客氣嘛  -下次吧
- You're too polite. - Next time.
王媽  三哥他們都餓了  我們吃吧
They're all starving, we can eat.
跟明哥說了沒有
Have you spoken to Ming?
那么我跟別人去
So I'll go with someone else.
講著玩的
Just kidding.
我會早點下班  你也早點回來
I'll be early tonight, see you soon.
-再見  -再見
- Bye! - Bye!
阿周
Chow.
來啦
Coming.
周  下班了  東西留著明天做
Time to go, finish it tomorrow.
做的差不多了  弄完再走了
No, I'm nearly there.
明哥
Oh, Ming.
-我下個月想請幾天假  -干什么
- I need a few days off next month. - Why?
答應跟太太去旅行  都說了好幾年
I promised my wife a trip.
你幫幫我
Put in a word for me, will you?
好吧  我跟人事部講講
I'll speak to personnel.
不過  你可要請吃飯
But the next lunch is on you.
怎樣都行
I'll.
多謝你明哥
Thanks, Ming.
好了  好了
It's ready.
還沒呢  飯熟了那個鍵會跳起來
No, it'll switch itself off.
哪有這么快  你這鄉下人
I told you, it's not ready.
電飯鍋啊  新買的  顧太太
A rice cooker, it's yours, Mrs. Koo?
像我們這些老古板
No, it's beyond us.
哪曉得買這種東西  是陳太太的
It's Mrs. Chan's.
我先生從日本帶回來的
My husband brought it from Japan.
我看挺好  所以介紹給顧太太
I wanted to show Mrs. Koo how good it is.
跳起來了  跳起來了
Now it's ready.
這回真行了  你看多方便
It's workable, you can see.
陳太太
Mrs. Chan.
麻煩你陳先生  下次幫我帶一個回來
Could Mr.Chan get me one next time?
好  沒問題
No problem.
周先生  你也應該買上一個
Mr.Chow, you should get one too.
你太太老是值夜班  有了它就方便多了
Your wife's so often late home.
麻煩陳先生不太好意思
I couldn't trouble Mr.Chan.
隔壁鄰居  無所謂啦
It's just neighborly, isn't it?
不要緊  他過兩天會再去
It's no trouble.
我叫他多帶一個回來
I'll ask him to buy another next time.
那么多謝你了
Thank you.
來  我們嘗嘗
Let's try the rice.
真不好意思  要你老遠帶電飯鍋給我
Mr.Chan, sorry to trouble you about the rice cooker.
順手的嘛  用不著客氣
It was really no trouble.
還沒付錢你  該多少錢
How much do I owe you?
你太太已經給我了
Your wife has already paid me.
是嗎
Really?
她沒告訴你
She didn't tell you?
她這陣子值夜班
She's been working late shifts.
等她回來我已經睡了
Often I'm asleep when she gets back.
在酒店做事也真辛苦
It must be hard for her.
是啊
Yes.
陳太太還沒回來
Mrs. Chan isn't back yet?
我想她快回來了  你有事找她
She'll be back soon, you need to talk to her?
我有個朋友過兩天去新加坡
A friend needs to go to Singapore.
想看看陳太太的公司有沒有  便宜點的船票
I wonder if she could get a cheap ticket for him.
等她回來我告訴她
I'll ask when she gets back.
麻煩你們不好意思
I'm bothering you too much.
客什么氣  大家隔壁鄰居  應該的
Don't mention it, we're neighbors.
那么我先回去了
I'll leave you in peace.
怎么  找我
Looking for me?
打著鑼找呢  整個上午到哪兒去了
Damn right, where've you been?
什么事呀
What's up?
陳太太打電話來
Mrs. Chan called.
說你把帽子忘在她公司了
you left a hat at her office.
我故意的  不然哪有機會多看她兩眼
I meant to, I wanted an excuse to go back.
早知你會來這一手
I know your tricks.
人家可是有老公的
She's married.
我當然知道她有老公
I know.
要不我還回來干嘛
That's why I left,
干脆搬到你那兒去
otherwise I'd move in next door.
說真的  幸好你老婆也是美人
If your wife wasn't so attractive,
要不然我可要替她擔心
she'd be a worried woman.
你當我是你啊
I'm not like you.
幫我打電話約陳太太
Please call Mrs. Chan for me.
說我明天上她公司拿帽子
I'll pick up the hat tomorrow.
順便請她喝茶
And take her to lunch.
你想得美
Dream on, I asked her to
我跟她說了  把帽子先拿回家
take the hat home.
明早我幫你帶回來
I'll bring it in tomorrow.
真泄氣  還是老朋友呢
You're kidding, some buddy you are.
索性我跟你回家去
Tell you what, let's go pick up now.
這個鐘點應該下班了
She should be off work by now.
一塊兒接她下班去
We can go together.
懶得跟你講
I don't have time for this.
阿周
Chow.
來啦  快走吧  我還要忙
Yes, get out of here, I'm busy.
這樣吧  我先走  在家等你
Then I'll wait at your place.
就這么說定了
That's all.
炳  炳
Ping, Ping.
周先生  顧先生在不在
Mr.Chow, is Mr.Koo in?
他出去了  又忘了買報紙了
He's out, forgot to buy the paper again?
是  我待會兒再來
That's right, I'll stop by later.
-我幫你找找看  -謝謝你
- Maybe I can find it for you. - Thank you!
-是這一張嗎  -是的
- This one? - Yes.
我以前也常看的  一天不看就不自在
I always loved those serials, hated to miss an episode.
是嗎  你也喜歡看武俠小說
Really? You like them too?
迷過一陣子  我還想過自己寫
I even thought of writing one.
為什么沒寫
Why didn't you?
想來想去開不了頭  也就算了
I couldn't get started, so I gave up.
注定不是干這一行的
I wasn't born to write martial arts stories.
那些武俠小說我都留著  要看你拿去
But you can borrow from my collection any time.
不了  下回再麻煩你  謝謝你
Not now, maybe another time, thanks.
不客氣
You're welcome.
什么事  陳太太
What is it, Mrs. Chan?
這些書還給周先生的  他在不在家
I just want to return these to Mr.Chow is he in?
他好幾天沒回來
He's been away for a few days.
怎么回事
Why?
兩夫妻吵架了
They had a quarrel.
你把書擱下吧  等周先生回來
Leave them with me.
我幫你還給他
I'll pass them back to him.
謝謝
Thank you!
不用了
Forget it.
今晚我值夜班
I'm on a replacement shift tonight.
你先回去吧
Talk to you later.
再說吧  今晚我會遲一點  你不用來接我了
No need to pick me up.
她已經走啦
She's already left.
是嗎  還想接她一塊吃夜宵
Really? I was going to take her out for supper.
她沒告訴你嗎  她今天早下班
Didn't she tell you she was off early today.
她老是這樣  顛三倒四的
She never remembers to tell me.
說不定已經回到家里了
Maybe she's home by now.
那我先走了
I'll be off, then.
好的  再見
Okay, bye!
你好
Hello!
你出院了嗎
You're out of hospital?
先別說了  借我三十塊
Don't mention hospital, lend me $30.
干什么
What for?
幫幫忙  名譽攸關
You gotta help me save face.
出了什么大事
What's the big deal?
還不是那個阿海  那天來醫院看我
It's Ah Hoi's fault.
說有內幕消息  穩贏的
He gave me a racing tip, said it was a sure thing.
我看他那么有把握  線都來不及拆
Before they'd taken out the stitches.
一股勁跑出醫院  趕去馬場
I rushed from hospital to Race Course.
把老婆本都押上了
I bet everything I had
結果輸了個精光
and I lost my shirt.
活該  剛開完刀還要去賭
What did you expect?
我想負傷上陣  必有大運
I thought it was my lucky day.
誰知輸剩兩塊錢
Anyhow, I had only $2 left.
賭氣就跑去找貴妃
So I went to the whorehouse.
病到這樣子你還要去玩女人啊
You were in no shape for sex.
想沖沖喜嘛
I thought it would improve for sex.
不是只剩兩塊錢  夠嗎
What would $2 buy you?
我是常客  好商量  先賒著也可以的
I'm Kwai Fei's regular, she gives me credit.
這種事情也可以賒賬
You can have in on credit?
把身份證押給她
I left my ID card and
說好兩三天后回去拿
said I'd be back to redeem it.
原以為這么一點錢很容易
I thought a few dollars would be back easy to rustle up.
誰知到現在還沒搞定  還過了期
But so far nothing. I'm way overdue.
那怎辦
So?
怎辦  昨兒小四上去
Four Eyes was there yesterday.
可不就看見她拿著我那張身份證
Saw her waving my ID around in
到處讓人看
front of everyone.
你說衰不衰啊
So embarrassing?
先別說了  給我三十塊
Anyway, lend me $30.
我只有那么多
This is all can spare.
留十塊  這些你拿去用
I need $10 for myself.
月初就還你
Pay you back next month.
-去吃宵夜  -還要吃宵夜
- Let's have a late snack. - What?
一整天就吃了一碗云吞面  都快餓死了
All I've had today is some won-ton noodles.
等我寫好這一段吧
Let me finish writing this first.
有件事  我不知道要不要跟你說
I'm not sure I should tell you this.
什么事
What?
昨天在街上看見你老婆
I saw your wife in the street yesterday.
這有什么好奇怪的
So what?
奇怪倒不奇怪
That is nothing,
不過她好像跟一個男人走在一起
but she was with some guy.
可能是她朋友
Probably a friend.
說得也對  我不過是隨便說說而已
Just thought you should know.
余小姐嗎  我是蘇秘書啊
Miss Yu? This is me.
何先生還在談事情
Mr.Ho's still in a meeting.
他說晚上恐怕不能跟你吃飯
he says he can't manage dinner.
是  我們這陣子很忙
Yes, we're very busy now.
好的  我會跟他說  再見
I'll, I'll ask Mr.Ho to call.
-你跟余小姐說了沒有  -說過了
- Have you called Miss Yu? - Yes, I've.
她怎么說
What did she say?
她叫你晚一點給她電話
Asks you to call her later.
何太太來過電話  說快切蛋糕了
And Mrs. Ho says she's ready to cut her birthday cake.
叫你快回去
She wants you to hurry home.
-禮物買了沒有  -買了
- Did you get me something to give her? - Yes, this.
-是什么東西  -是圍巾
- What is it? - A scarf.
-我想何太太會喜歡吧  -麻煩你了
- I think Mrs. Ho will like it. - Thank you.
用剩的錢
And here's your change.
不用了  你拿著  老是麻煩你
I'm always troubling you,
車費也要的
use it for bus fare.
不如  到我家吃頓便飯
Why don't you dine with us tonight?
別客氣  我約了我先生看電影
Thank you, I've already planned to see a film tonight.
那就不妨礙你們了
Then I won't keep you.
明天上午沒什么事
Tomorrow will be quiet.
你可以下午才回來
Take the morning off.
-再見  -再見
- Goodbye! - Goodbye!
你今天晚上會出去嗎
Are you going out tonight?
記得拿鑰匙
Don't forget your keys.
孫太太他們去吃喜酒
All the neighbors are dining out tonight.
公司很忙  我會晚點回來
I have a lot to do here so I'll be late.
什么事  陳太太
What is it, Mrs. Chan?
我聽見隔壁有聲音
I heard voices.
還以為是顧先生顧太太回來
I thought Mr.& Mrs. Koo were back.
還沒有  你找他們有事
Not yet, anything I can help with?
沒什么  找他們聊聊天
No, I just wanted a chat.
-你一個人  -是
- Are you alone? - Yes, I am.
這么早回來
You're back early today?
有點不舒服  就早點回來了
I'm not feeling well, I came back to rest.
你哪里不舒服  我有藥
What is it? I have some medicines.
不用了  我睡會兒就好
Don't trouble yourself, I'll sleep it off.
好  我不打擾了
In that case, I'll leave you in peace.
你的老婆
It was your wife.
跟你老婆說了沒有
Have you spoken to your wife yet?
那么你以后別再找我
Then we shouldn't meet any more.
菲律賓那邊有沒有消息
Any news from the Philippines?
剛收到電報
Yes, a telex.
說那邊刮臺風  船都不能開
There's a typhoon, so the ship's still docked.
那么你馬上通知陳先生
Please inform Chan.
說他那批貨可能要晚一兩天才能到
That the shipment may be delayed.
問他有沒有問題
Ask if that's a problem.
何太太打過電話來
Your wife rang,
說用不著回家去接她
you don't need to pick her up.
她在跟劉太太打牌
She's playing mahjong with Mrs. Lau.
你五點半直接上天香樓找她便行
She'll meet you at the restaurant at 5:30,
余小姐有一份禮物交給你
and there's a gift from Miss Yu.
她上來過
She was here?
不  她找人送上來的
No, she had it sent over.
她說知道你今天生日  應酬多
She says she'll dine alone since it's your birthday.
所以不找你吃飯了
Please phone her
叫你有空再給她電話
when you have a moment.
-我幫你倒杯咖啡  -謝謝
- I'll get you another coffee. - Thank you!
謝謝
Thank you!
領帶很漂亮
That tie looks good on you.
你看得出我換了領帶嗎
You noticed?
我還以為差不多
It's much like the old one.
仔細看能看出來
You notice things if you pay attention.
我先走了
I'll be off now.
如果陳先生那邊有問題
If Chan has a problem,
打電話到天香樓找我
let me know at the restaurant.
怎么把領帶又換了
Why did you change your tie?
我嫌那條太花俏了點兒
The new one was too showy.
還是換回原來的好
I should stick with my own.
記得鎖門啊
Don't forget to lock up.
對了  最近很少看見你先生
By the way, haven't seen your husband lately.
是呀  這陣子他公司有事  派了他出去
He's abroad now, on company business.
怪不得老在面攤碰見你
That's why I see you at the noodle stall.
一個人懶得煮飯
I don't like cooking for myself.
對了  你太太呢  最近也很少看見她
Haven't seen your wife lately either.
她媽媽身體不太舒服  回娘家陪陪她
Her mother's ill, she's at home with her.
難怪了
That explains it.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night! - Good night!
陳太太  你回來就好了
Mrs. Chan, I'm glad you're back.
外面雨下得那么兇
It's raining so hard.
我還想打傘去接你呢
I was going to look for you with and umbrella.
不過是陣頭雨  你有心
You are too kind.
王媽  是誰
Amah, who is it?
是陳太太
It's Mrs. Chan.
孫太太
Mrs. Suen.
哎呀  下那么大雨還出去呀
Caught in the rain? I said you could
大家自己人  早叫你一道吃
eat with us.
下回吧  慢慢打
Next time, Enjoy your game.
哎呀  她先生一天到晚在外頭
Her husband's always away.
她一個人孤伶伶怪可憐的
It's sad to see her to lonely.
出去買碗面  還穿得真漂亮
She dresses up like that to go out for noodle.
周先生  怎么到這邊來了
Mr.Chow, What are you doing here?
我過來叫顧太太聽電話
Just calling Mrs. Koo to the phone.
這么晚
You're late back.
剛看了場電影
I went to the picture.
我先回去了
I'll be going.
喂
Hello!
啊  你等等啊
Yes, please hold on.
-是誰的電話  -陳太太的電話
- Who is it? - It's for Mrs. Chan.
那么冒昧約你出來  是有點事想請教你
It must seem odd to ask you, out but I want to ask something.
你今天下午拿著的皮包
That handbag I saw you with this evening.
不知道哪里有的買
Where did you buy it?
你為什么這樣問
Why do you ask?
哦  我看款式很別致
It looked so elegant.
想買一個送給我太太
I want to get one for my wife.
周先生對太太真細心
Mr.Chow, you're so good to your wife.
那里  她這人很挑剔
Not really, my wife is so fussy.
過兩天她生日
Her birthday is two days away.
不知道買什么送給她才好
I don't know what to get her.
你可不可以幫我買一個
Could you buy one for me to give her?
要是一模一樣的  她會不喜歡吧
Maybe she wouldn't want one just exactly the same.
說的也是  我倒也沒想到
You're right, I didn't think of that.
女人會介意  對吧
Women would mind.
會的  特別是隔壁鄰居
Yes, especially since we're neighbors.
不知道會不會有別的顏色
Do they come in other colors?
那要問我先生才知道
I'd have to ask my husband.
為什么
Why?
那皮包是我先生
He bought it for me
在外地工作的時候買給我的
on a business trip abroad.
他說在香港沒有賣的
They aren't on sale here.
那就算了吧
Then never mind.
其實
Actually.
我也有一件事情想請教你
I want to ask your something too.
什么事
What?
你的領帶在哪里買的
Where did you buy your tie?
我還真的不知道
I don't know where it came from.
我領帶全是我太太幫我買的
My wife buys all my ties.
是嗎
Really?
我想起來了  有一次她公司派她出去
She bought this one
回來送給我的
on a business trip abroad.
她說香港沒有賣的
It's not on sale here.
倒有這么巧
What a coincidence!
是啊
Yes.
其實
Actually.
我先生也有條領帶跟你的一模一樣
My husband has one just like it.
他說是他老板送他的
He said it was a gift from his boss.
所以天天戴著
So he wears it every day.
我太太也有個皮包跟你那個一模一樣
Any my wife has a bag just like yours.
我知道  我見過
I know, I have seen it.
你想說什么
What are you getting at, actually?
我還以為只有我一個人知道
I thought I was the only one who knew.
不知道他們是怎樣開始的
I wonder how it began.
你這么晚不回家  你老婆不說你嗎
It's late, won't your wife complain?
早習慣了  她不管我的
She's used to it, she doesn't care.
你呢  你老公不說什么嗎
And your husband?
我想他早睡了
He must be asleep by now.
今晚別回去了
Shall we stay out tonight?
我老公不會這樣講的
My husband would never say that.
他會怎么講
What would he say?
就是不會講
Anyhow, he wouldn't say that.
總有一個人先開口吧
Someone must have made the first move.
不是他是誰
Who else could it be?
你這么晚不回家  你老婆不會問嗎
It's late, won't your wife complain?
早習慣了  她不管的
She's used to it, she doesn't care.
你老公不會說什么嗎
And your husband?
我想他早睡了
He must be asleep by now.
我真的說不出口
I can't say it.
我明白
I understand.
事到如今
After all, it's already happened.
誰先開口有什么所謂
It doesn't matter who made the first move.
其實你知不知道你老婆是怎樣的人
Do you really know your wife?
你幫我點
You order for me.
為什么
Why?
我想知道你老婆喜歡吃什么
I've no idea what your wife likes.
那么你丈夫喜歡吃什么
What about your husband?
吃得慣嗎
Like it hot?
你老婆挺能吃辣的
Your wife likes hot dishes.
為什么打電話到我公司
Why did you call me at the office today?
沒事做  想聽聽你的聲音
I had nothing to do, I want to hear your voice.
學得倒挺像我老公
You have my husband down pat.
油嘴滑舌
He's real sweet-talker.
你為什么不打電話給我
Why didn't you call me today?
怕你會不高興
I was afraid you won't like it.
那么以后不要再打電話給我
Then don't call me again.
陳太太  陳先生有封信來了  你看看
Mrs. Chan, a letter from your husband.
不是我的  是隔壁周先生的
It's not for me, it's for Mr.Chow next door.
我看見信封上的日本郵票
The Japanese stamp made me think
以為是陳先生寄來
it was your husband.
原來不是
So I was wrong.
你老婆去了日本
Your wife's in Japan?
你怎么知道
How did you know?
信里寫些什么
What did she say in her letter?
沒什么
Nothing special.
有沒有說幾時回來
Anything about when she'd be back?
沒有
No.
你猜他們現在在做什么
What do you think they're doing right now?
-你沒事吧  -沒事
- Are you alright? - I'm fine.
麻煩你在前面停停車
Please pull up here.
干什么
Why?
我先下車
I'll get off first.
不好  我先下
No, let me.
-陳太太  -炳哥  你回來了
- Mrs. Chan. - Ah Ping, you're back.
-是啊  -找周先生
- Visiting. - Mr.Chow?
想找他喝茶  哪知道他病了
Yes, I thought we'd have lunch but he isn't well.
怎么回事
What's wrong with him?
發燒  他老婆又不在家
He's got fever, he's all alone.
一個人怪可憐的  下去給他買點什么吃
So I'm gonna buy him something to eat.
街口那家店  賣的粥挺好的
The congee downstairs is quite good.
他不想吃粥
He doesn't want congee.
他想吃什么
What does he want?
他說嘴里淡得慌  想吃芝麻糊
Can't taste anything, so he wants sesame syrup.
真難纏
Damned troublesome.
王媽  王媽
Amah.
孫太太  王媽上天臺晾衣服去了
Mrs. Suen, she's hanging the washing on the roof.
你回來了
You're back.
這是剛上街回來
Yes, you've been out?
是呀  下禮拜我媽過生日
My mother's birthday is coming up.
我帶她去買點布料做新衣
So I took her to buy some fabric.
跑了一整天  氣都喘不上來了
It took all day, I'm half dead.
順道燙了個頭發  好看嗎
And I had my hair done, is it nice?
很漂亮
Very nice!
你在煮什么
What are you cooking?
忽然想吃芝麻糊
I had a sudden craving for sesame syrup.
一大鍋你怎么吃呀
That whole pot is for you.
反正煮了  大家一塊吃吧
I thought I might as well make a potful.
你真客氣
You're so thoughtful.
-來一碗吧  -好啊
- Please try it. - I'll.
這么巧
What a coincidence.
是啊  上街嗎
Going out?
整晚沒吃過東西了  下來吃碗面
I'll buy some noodles, I'm starving.
你餓不餓  一起啊
Hungary? Will you join me?
不了
No thanks.
這么晚才下班
Just off work?
公司很忙
You must be very busy.
就是沒事做  所以看了場電影
Actually, I've been to see a picture.
是嗎  好不好看
Really? How was it?
馬馬虎虎
So-so.
我從前也愛看電影
I used to like going to the pictures.
你以前倒是挺多嗜好的
You had many hobbies before.
自己一個人  大把時間  想做什么就做什么
On your own, you are free to do lots of things.
結了婚就不一樣
Everything changes when you marry.
很多事情  一個人作不了主
It must be decided together.
對不對
Right?
有時候我會想  要是現在還沒有結婚
I sometimes wonder what I'd be.
不知會怎樣
if I hadn't married.
你也會這樣想嗎
Have you ever thought of that?
可能會比較開心吧
Maybe happier.
我以前都沒有想到婚姻
I didn't know married life would be.
是這樣復雜
so complicated.
如果一個人  自己做得好就夠了
When you're single, you are only responsible to yourself
可是當兩個人在一起時
Once you're married,
只有自己做得好是不夠的
doing well on your own is not enough.
別想太多了  等他們回來再說吧
Don't brood on it, maybe he'll be back soon.
你沒事啊
What about you?
其實我跟你還不是一樣
Actually, we're in the same boat.
我只是不去想
But I don't brood on it.
又不是我做錯
It's not my fault.
何必每天問自己做錯了什么
I can't waste time wondering if I made mistakes.
浪費自己時間
Life's too short for that.
我不想這樣下去
Something must change.
你有什么打算
So what's your plan?
這幾天我躺在床上翻武俠小說
I want to write a martial-arts
我想再寫
serial...
已經開了頭  過兩天讓你看
Actually, I've started one, I'll show it to you.
好啊
Great!
你這么喜歡看武俠小說
You like them too.
我們一起寫吧
so why not help me write it?
這怎么行  我只會看  哪里會寫
I wouldn't know how, I only read them.
試試看嘛
We would discuss it together.
那好吧  我盡量
Alright, I'll try my best.
還沒多謝你的芝麻糊呢
I never thanked you for the sesame syrup.
別客氣  小意思嘛
There's no need I was making it anyway.
說起來真巧
Amazing, I was craving for some
剛好那天我很想吃芝麻糊
sesame syrup that day.
是嗎  這么巧
Really? What's a coincidence.
是呀  就這么巧
It really was.
我先去吃點東西
I'll go for those noodles.
老是這樣子  酒席吃到一半就醉倒
Again, halfway through dinner, he's drunk.
真討厭
Disgusting!
-早說別給他喝了  -我有啥辦法
- I told you to stop. - What can you do?
是我
It's me.
嚇死我了
You scared me.
怎樣  顧先生有沒有事
How's Mr.Koo?
喝醉了吧
Drunk, as usual.
怎會這樣早
I didn't expect them back so early.
反正沒法子  不如先把面吃完再說
Since you're trapped here, finish the noodles.
我想他們坐一會兒就走
They'll probably go soon.
加點湯嗎
Want some soup?
要不要加點湯
孫太太  怎么在這邊打麻將
Mrs. Suen, playing here tonight.
顧太太說要看著她先生嘛
Yes, Mrs. Koo is dealing with her husband.
早跟我說嘛  我來照顧他就行了
I could do that.
怎好意思呀
No, we should not trouble you.
這樣高興  看來要玩到天亮
Think you'll play all night?
才不會  頂多八圈
No, we'll just play eight rounds.
你猜他們會不會打到天亮
They'll play till morning?
孫太太說只打八圈
Mrs. Suen says only eight rounds.
你信不信
You believe that?
不如你瞌睡一會  他們散了我就叫你
You get some rest, I'll wake you when they leave.
那你呢
And you?
我先把這段寫好
I have a chapter to finish.
寫到哪兒
Where have you got to?
大醉俠出場
The drunken master just showed up.
怎么多了個大醉俠
When did he get written in?
剛想到的
Just now.
周先生  這樣早就出去啊
Mr.Chow, home so early?
我下去買點吃的
I went out to buy some food.
你今天不用上班嗎
No work today?
有點不太舒服  告了一天假
I didn't feel so good, I'm staying home.
不舒服還吃這么多糯米雞
A sick man shouldn't eat all that sticky rice.
省得晚上再出去買
Some of it's for later.
當心吃撐了
Don't stuff yourself.
周先生
Good morning.
你早  散場了嗎  孫太太
Good morning, finished your game?
沒有呢  楊先生要辦公  讓他先走了
Not yet, but Mr.Yang has to work.
不過蔡先生馬上就來
Mr.Tsai is coming to replace him.
有沒有幫我打電話回公司請假
Did you call the office for me?
打過了
Yes.
你怎么說的
What did you tell them?
說你病了
That you weren't feeling well.
他們有沒有問你是誰
Did them ask who you were?
沒有
No.
多半以為我是你丈夫吧
Probably took me for your husband.
何先生知道他出門了
Mr.Ho knows that he's away.
就說他已經回來好了
Pretend he's come back.
都是自己嚇自己
Maybe we're being too cautious?
平日我也常過來
I'm always round anyway.
有什么好緊張的
We shouldn't have panicked.
這很難說  他們突然之間回來
Well, they did turn up without warning.
不知道他們會怎么亂想
What would they assume?
所以真的不能走錯一步
We can't put a foot wrong.
走吧
You can go.
-王媽  -陳太太  怎么這樣晚
- Amah. - Mrs. Chan, you're back very late.
是呀  今天公司事情多
I had a lot of work today.
怎么今早沒看見你上班
I didn't see you leave this morning.
今天很早約了媽媽喝茶
I had breakfast with my mother.
我出去的時候你還沒來
You weren't here when I left.
孫太太呢
Where's Mrs. Suen?
她搓麻將搓到天亮  才剛睡
Asleep, she played mahjong all day.
-別吵她了  -好的
- Be quiet, don't wake her. - Alright.
呀  陳太太  你的腳還好吧
Mrs. Chan, is your leg alright?
沒什么  新鞋子太窄  擠腳了
It's these new shoes.
干嘛請我吃飯
Why a special dinner tonight?
今天出稿費  你那一份你又不收
Since you won't take your share of
只好請你吃飯了
the writing fee.
其實不關我的事
None of my business.
我在旁邊打打邊鼓而已
All I did was give you some thoughts.
我也許會多寫一家報紙
Someone else is asking for a serial too.
今天有人打電話來約稿
There'll be more work soon.
是嗎  那太好了
Really? So quickly.
你應付得了嗎
Isn't the workload too much?
所以想找一個地方
That's why I'm looking for a new place.
做什么
What for?
寫東西
To write in,
這樣你以后上來都方便點嘛
it'll be more convenient.
雖然我們之間沒什么
There's nothing between us,
但是我不想別人誤會你
but I don't want gossip.
你覺得怎樣
What do you think?
太浪費了
Why waste money?
其實都是你自己寫的
You don't need me,
何必多此一舉呢
you can write on your own.
喂  找誰呀
Who do you want?
周慕云
Chow Mo-Wan?
他沒上班好幾天了
He hasn't been in for several days.
我們也到處在找他
We're looking for him too.
你是哪位啊
May I know who's calling?
要留個話嗎
Any message?
哦  不用謝  多掛來啊
It's no trouble, goodbye.
這文件馬上送去會計部
Please get this to Accounts.
還有  冷氣機明天叫人來看看
And have the air-conditioner serviced tomorrow.
好  何先生
Mr.Ho.
沒什么事了  你可以走了
No need to stay if everything's done.
-門我來鎖嘍  -好的
- I'll lock up. - Yes.
喂
Hello?
你在哪里啊
Where are you?
我明天再來看你
I'll come again tomorrow.
我歇兩天就沒事
No need, I'll be alright after some rest.
不要緊  才一會兒功夫
It's no trouble.
我給你買點吃的  你想吃什么
I'll bring you some food, what would you like?
隨便
Whatever.
那我就走了  你早點休息
Then I'll leave now, get some rest.
回去給我個電話
Call me when you get home.
用不著說話  響三聲就好
Let it ring three times then hang up.
好
Alright.
我沒想過你會來
I didn't think you'd come.
我們不會跟他們一樣的
We won't be like them.
明天見
See you tomorrow.
你老實告訴我
Tell me honestly.
你外面是不是有個女人
Do you have a mistress?
神經病
You're crazy.
誰跟你說的
Who told you I had?
你別管
Never mind who.
你是不是有了個女人
Do you or don't you?
沒有
No.
不要騙我
Don't lie.
你看著我  你看著我
Look at me.
我問你  你外面是不是有個女人
I'm asking you, do you have a mistress.
是
Yes.
你怎么了
That's no reaction.
他已經承認在外面有個女人
If he admits it outright,
你還打得這么輕
let him have it.
我沒想到他會回答得這樣干脆
I wasn't expecting he would admit it so easily.
我不知道該怎么辦
I didn't know how to react.
再來一次吧
One more time, alright?
你老實回答我
Tell me frankly.
你外面是不是有個女人
Do you have a mistress?
神經病
You're crazy.
誰跟你說的
Who told you that?
你別管  你是不是有個女人
Never mind that, do you or don't you?
沒有
No.
你不要騙我
Don't lie.
你告訴我
Tell me.
你看著我  是不是有個女人
Look at me, do you have a mistress?
是
Yes.
你沒事吧
Are you alright?
我沒想到真的會這樣傷心
I didn't expect it to hurt so much.
我試試而已  又不是真的
This is just a rehearsal.
就算是真的他也不會認
He won't really admit it so readily.
沒事的  別這樣
It's alright, don't take it so hard.
你最近好像應酬挺多的
You've been out a lot lately
是啊
Yes.
年紀輕呢  出去散散心是應該的
It's right to enjoy yourself while you're young.
不過得有分寸
But don't overdo it.
你先生幾時回來
When will your husband be back?
他快回來了
Soon.
等他回來呢  別再讓他老出門
In future, don't let him travel so much.
兩夫妻經常分開呢  總不大好
A couple should spend time together.
你說對嗎
Don't you agree?
晚安
Good night!
你今天晚上過不過來
Will you come over tonight?
做什么
What for?
這兩天給催稿  說我寫得慢
The editor's hounding me, he says I'm too slow.
過來幫忙手啊  你幾點可以
I need your help, when can you come?
我想這陣子我不過來了
Not anytime soon.
怎么了
Why not?
昨晚回家  讓孫太太說了幾句
Mrs. Suen lectured me last night.
她說你什么
What did he say?
我不想講
Rather not say.
反正這陣子我們還是少點見面吧
We shouldn't see so much of each other.
陳太太  又要去買面啊
Mrs. Chan, going out for noodles again?
今天不去了
Not tonight, I'll make myself something.
隨便弄點什么吃的就算了
Join us, we're having vegetable won-tons.
那好的
Alright.
-何先生沒出去吃午飯  -沒有
- No lunch today, Mr.Ho? - No.
剛才有位周先生打電話找你
Now one Mr.Zhou call you.
叫你回電話給他
He wants you to call him back.
謝謝
Thank you.
-下班啦  -是呀
- Back from work? - Yes.
-這真是大雨呀  -是呀
- Strange weather, isn't it. - Yes.
在這兒站很久了
Been here long?
一會兒罷了
Just a while.
我想還得下好一會兒
I don't think it'll stop soon.
你等等我
Wait for me.
我送你回去
I'll see you home.
讓人看見  又話多了
We'd better not be seen together.
那么你先回去
Then you go first.
他們認得你的傘
If they see your umbrella.
我撐著回去  不也一樣
They'll know I was with you.
這也是  我倒沒想到
I wasn't thinking.
你先回去吧  我待一會兒就回
You go first, I'll wait a while.
我陪你
I'll keep you company.
你找過我
Did you try to call me?
還以為你同事忘了告訴你
I wasn't sure you got the message.
想找你買張船票
Could you get me a boat ticker?
你要去別的地方
To where?
阿炳來過很多信
Ah Ping wrote from Singapore.
說那邊缺人手  要我去幫他忙
They're short of staff, he'd like me to go and help.
打算去多久
How long will you stay?
不知道  去了再說吧
Don't know, I'll play it be ear.
怎么突然會想去新加坡
Why rush off to Singapore?
想換一下環境...
A change of scene...
免得聽著太多的閑言閑語
I've had enough of the gossip.
我們自己知道我們沒什么不就行了
We know it's not true, so why worry?
原來我也這樣想
I used to think that too,
所以不怕別人說閑話
and it didn't worry me.
我相信我自己不會像他們那樣
I thought we wouldn't be like them.
原來會的
But I was wrong.
我知道你不會離開你丈夫
You won't leave your husband.
我想離開一下
So I'd rather go away.
我沒有想過你真的會喜歡我
I didn't think you'd fall in love with me.
我也沒有想過
I didn't either.
我一直在想  他們是怎樣開始的
I was only curious to know how it started.
現在我明白了
Now I know.
原來很多事情都這樣
Feelings can creep up just like that.
我還以為自己沒有什么
I thought I was in control.
但是開始擔心你丈夫幾時會回來
But I hate to think of our husband coming home.
最好不要回來
I wish he'd stay away.
我知道這樣想不對
I'm so bad.
你能不能幫我一個忙
Will you do me one favour?
做什么
What?
我想有點心理準備
I want to be prepared.
以后不要再找我了
You'd better not see me again.
你老公他回來了
Is your husband back?
是啊
Yes.
我真沒用
Am I hopeless?
不是啊
Not really.
我不會再找你了
I won't see you again.
好好地守著你的丈夫
Keep a closer eye on your husband.
別這樣
Please.
說了試著的嘛
Don't be serious it's only a rehearsal.
別哭
Don't cry.
這又不是真的
This isn't real.
我今天晚上不想回家
I don't want to go home tonight.
陳美儀點給好朋友權仔和文文
Mei-Yi wants to dedicate a song
祝他們成功
to her honeymooning friends.
又點給同屋的張太太收聽
And Mrs. Cheung wishes the best to
祝家庭幸福
her neighbors.
有一位在日本公干的陳先生
And Mr.Chan, now on business in Japan
點這首歌給他太太
wants to wish his wife
祝她生日快樂  工作順利
a happy birthday.
現在請大家一起欣賞  周璇唱的
So let's all enjoy Zhou Xuan singing.
花樣的年華
In Full Bloom.
是我
It's me.
如果有多一張船票
If there's an extra ticket.
你會不會跟我一起走
Would you go with me?
是我
It's me.
如果有多一張船票
If there's an extra ticket.
你會不會帶我一起走
Would you go with me?
哈羅  周先生不在  他上班去了
Mr.Chow has gone to work.
有話要轉達嗎
Any message?
不用謝  拜拜
You're welcome.
是不是有人進過我房間
Has anyone been in my room?
沒有呀
No.
沒有  我丟了東西
Something's missing.
丟了什么呀
What?
你知不知道  從前的人
In the old days.
要是心里有了秘密  不想別人知道
If someone had a secret they didn't want to share.
你知不知道他們會怎樣做
You know what they did?
我怎么知道
Have no idea.
他們會跑到山上找一棵樹
They went up to a mountain, found a tree.
在樹上挖個洞
Carved a hole in it.
然后把秘密全說進去
And whispered the secret into the hole.
再用泥巴封起來
Then they covered it with mud.
那秘密就永遠留在那棵樹里  沒人知道
And leave the secret there forever.
這樣辛苦  找個女人發泄一下不更好
What a pain, I'd just go to get laid.
誰都像你呀
Not everyone's like you.
說得是呀  像我這樣的人
I'm just an average guy.
是個直腸子  哪來的心事呀
I don't have secrets like you?
你可不同  什么都往心里擱
You bottle things up.
說來聽聽嘛
Tell me something.
我哪有心事
I don't have secrets.
你別瞞我啦  一場朋友
Come off it, buddy.
我不會跟別人說的
I won't tell anyone.
喂  你好  星洲日報
Hello, Singapore Daily.
請等等
Hold on.
云哥  電話
Mr.Chow, call for you.
謝謝
Thanks.
喂
Hello!
-誰呀  -王媽  是我啊
- Who is it? - It is me.
-陳太太  好久沒見了  -是呀
- Mrs. Chan, long time no see. - Yes.
-王媽  什么人呀  -孫太太
- Amah, who's there? - Mrs. Suen.
哎呀  你怎么會過來啊
What brings you here?
是啊  很久沒來這里看你
It's been a while.
今天剛好經過這里
I was nearby
特意把船票帶給你
so I thought I'd bring your boat ticket.
請你吃的
And a small gift.
哎呀  上來坐坐就好了  還這樣客氣  又破費
You shouldn't have, it's nice just to see you.
你看這屋里亂七八糟的
The place is in such a mess.
你還在收拾啊
Already started packing?
已經收拾好幾天了
It's hopeless,
東西太多  有些又舍不得扔
I can't bear to throw things away.
-坐的地方都沒有  到這邊坐  -好啊
- Let's find you a seat. - OK.
-吃茶  -謝謝  王媽
- Have some tea. - Thank you!
你今天別走  在這里吃晚飯  我去買菜
Eat with us, Mrs. Chan, I'm going to the market.
不行呢  我還得回公司辦點事
I can't, I have work waiting.
你干嘛急著走
Don't rush off,
你不留在這兒吃飯
if you don't eat here.
太太要不高興的  太太
Mrs. Suen will be upset.
噯  你替我倒杯茶來
Amah, pour me some tea too.
陳先生好嗎
How's your husband?
挺好的  有心了
He's fine, thank you.
你打算走多久
How long will you be away?
我也不曉得
I don't know.
要是住的慣呢我就不回來了
If I like it, I might stay.
為什么
Why?
我女兒說現在香港這么亂
My daughter worries about the situation in Hong Kong.
我自己一個人在這邊她不放心
She worry about I stay alone in Hong Kong.
我倒是舍不得離開香港的
I don't want to leave.
不過自從顧先生他們搬走了以后
Since the Koos left.
搓麻將也沒搭伴
I don't have my mahjong partners anymore.
想想呢  還是到美國去給女兒帶孩子算了
And my daughter needs help with her kids in the US.
這房子怎么辦
What about this place?
正為了這個傷腦筋嘛
I'm not sure.
賣出去呢真不舍得
I don't want to sell it.
想想還是租給人家吧
So I might rent it out.
你打算租多少錢
How much would you want?
噯  你有意思租嗎
You're interested?
租給你我可就放心了  我便宜點租給你啦
You could have it at a discount.
我想想看
I'll think about it.
太太  吃茶
Mrs. Suen, your tea.
對了  現在是什么人住在隔壁
Who lives next door now?
我也不大曉得  不像以前  都沒往來
I don't really know them.
以前跟顧先生顧太太不知多熱鬧
The Koos were almost like family.
像一家人一樣  想起來也開心
It was so nice then.
你說是嗎
wasn't it?
是啊
Yes.
過來這邊坐
Let's sit over here.
你找哪位
Yes?
請問顧先生在不在
Is Mr.Koo in?
顧先生  搬了好久了
He moved long ago.
知不知道搬到哪兒去了
Do you know where he is?
你跟他很熟嗎
You know him well?
我從前住在這里
I used to live here.
孫太太還住在隔壁嗎
Is Mrs. Suen still next door?
也搬了  現在亂成這樣
She's gone, it's too chaotic.
能走的還不走嗎
Everyone's running away.
現在隔壁住著什么人
So who lives there now?
我也不太清楚
I am not sure.
好像就是一個女人帶著她兒子
A woman and her son.
那小孩子蠻可愛的
The kid is cute.
他菲律賓的地址我沒找著
No address in the Philippines.
只有他兒子的電話
Just his son's phone number.
-你拿回去  -這怎行
- I can't accept this. - How this.
小意思  不客氣
Please, you must.
-那么謝謝了  -慢走
- Thank you, then. - Bye.
庸生  好了沒
Are you ready?
-好了  -快點
- Okay. - Let's go.
柬埔寨首都機場上
The presidential corps waits at Pochentong Airport.
皇室人員上前
Prince Norodom Sihanouk and Queen sisowath Kossamak
迎接戴高樂將軍
come forward to greet General De Gaulle.
公路上列隊歡迎
It's ten kilometres from Pochentong to Phnom Penh.
人潮達二十萬人
200,000 people line the route.
寫下該國前所未有的一頁
A welcome unprecedented in the history of the Kingdom.